# **JEFFREY CHIU**



+1.347.589.4735

NYC Metropolitan Area







• jeffrey-chiu.medium.com

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A design-minded developer with a background in sales and client management. Experienced in JavaScript-based programming, especially React and Redux, as well as Ruby on Rails. Committed to consistency and transparency, dedicated to continuous development, and energized by a challenge.

## **SKILLS**

JavaScript • React • Redux • React Native • jQuery • Node.js • Ruby • Rails • HTML • CSS • SQL • PostgreSQL • SQLite • Git • Bootstrap • Materials UI • Semantics UI • WordPress

Fluent in Mandarin, Taiwanese, and Cantonese • Windows 10 • MAC OSX • Salesforce • CRM Systems • Microsoft Office Suite • Google Suite • Adobe Photoshop

# **PROJECTS**

**Alteri** (React, Redux, Rails, PostgreSQL, WebSockets, CSS) Web app connecting those in need of basic necessities with donors







- Integrated WebSockets through ActionCable to enable multiple connections; notifying the user of new requests being made, updates to their requests, as well as any new conversations or messages to the real-time chat feature.
- Implemented a map feature using the Google Maps API to show the current locations of the recipient and donor on each request.
- Enhanced global state management with Redux Toolkit for CRUD functions with a Rails RESTful API.
- Secured user authentication with Oauth and user info management.

**Spreddit** (React, Rails, PostgreSQL, CSS)

Functional *Reddit* clone to post about pandemic related topics

LIVE LINK





- Ensured a smooth user experience (UX) through React (hooks) and React Router for client-side routing.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Designed a RESTful API and implemented full CRUD functionality on posts, comments, and likes.

**YouTravel** (JavaScript, Rails, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, CSS) **YouTube** inspired site focused exclusively on travel videos

LIVE LINK





- Developed a single page app enabling users to view and post videos based on a selected city and video category. To post a video, users use a YouTube URL which is then parsed and saved as the embed link on the backend.
- Manipulated the DOM, allowing users to see new videos, likes, and comments, as well as any changes in real-time.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## **Web Development Volunteer**

**Stop Abuse Campaign** | New York, NY May 2021 - Present

- Developed wireframes into fully functional, responsive web pages by customizing Wordpress themes with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Improved the overall UX for visitors of the resources library; specifically domestic abuse victims in search of assistance for themselves and their children.

#### **Analyst, Business Development**

Factor | New York, NY

April 2019 - September 2020

- Developed and executed upon business plans in conjunction with various teams to build pipeline and revenue; resulting in 17 qualified opportunities totaling \$4 million across a variety of industries.
- Drove growth via outbound approach. Called on C-Suite executives, General Counsels, and potential clients, to identify potential engagements for Factor's next-generation legal solutions focused around process, workflow software, and contract management technology.
- Documented all activity within Salesforce.com; created reports, campaigns, and dashboards to track sales lifecycle.

#### **Account Executive**

Liagre, Inc | New York, NY

April 2018 - April 2019

- Identified stagnant accounts and developed customized plans, achieved \$1 million in sales within the first six months, 40% contributed from new leads or stagnant accounts.
- Increased brand exposure by cultivating relationships from an incumbent client book of over 400 interior design firms within eastern Canada, New York, and Washington DC.

#### **Assistant Showroom Manager, Account Executive**

Cassina | New York, NY

September 2014 - April 2018

- Ranked #1 nationally and #3 worldwide for sales in 2016, 2017, and first half of 2018.
- Managed high profile interior designers and clients to generate an average of \$1.3 million on an annual basis with a conversion rate of 80%.
- Oversaw and trained a team of three Account Executives; provided insight and support to ensure their continued success.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Flatiron School**

March 2021

Immersive Full-Stack Web Development Program Access Scholarship Recipient

#### **Bernard M. Baruch College**

May 2013

BBA: Advertising & Marketing Communications